睡得舒服吗 红蜘蛛？
Resting comfortably, Starscream?
尽管你伤得不轻
Despite the extend of your injuries
但我的医务兵向我保证 你很快就能康复
my medical staff assures me that you shall make a rapid recovery.
但愿您也快点消去心头的怒火
Hopefully, every bit as rapid as your wrath is swift.
真是世事难料啊
Hahahahahaha... and how swiftly things change?
想想看 不久之前
To think that but a short time ago
还是你站在这里 而我躺在那里
it was you who were standing here while I was lying there
可惜你棋差一着 没能置我于死地！
right after your failed attempt to terminate me.
不过你记好了 亲爱的红蜘蛛：
But know this, dear Starscream:
你再也休想翻身上位
our position shall never again be reversed.
红蜘蛛 你失去理智了吗？
Starscream, have you lost your senses?
你还没完全康复呢！
You haven't fully recuperated.
我感觉很好 击倒 再好不过了！
I feel fine, Knock Out, never better!
你真是神医啊 现在给我滚开！
You are a brilliant physician. Now get out of my way!
啊…黑暗能量让你恢复了力量 主人
Ahhh... Dark Energon may have replenished your strength, master.
但你难道忘了吗？\N你还没有拿回 你原本的那块碎片
But how could you forget, that you never reclaimed your original shard?
宇宙大帝之血流入我的血脉之日
Once the blood of Unicron flows through my veins
就是我翻身上位之时！
our positions shall be reversed.
原以为我对这种东西的了解 仅限于学术方面
I had hoped that my growing expertise on the subject would remain purely academic
但这个微弱的信号 显然又是一股黑暗能量
but though faint, this is clearly a Dark Energon signature
而且移动迅速
and it's moving fast.
是威震天
Megatron.
他又从哪儿找到了那东西？
Where did he find more the bad stuff?
他用那能量要干嘛？组建新的丧尸大军吗？
What's he gonna do with it? Recruiting new army of the undead?
僵尸虎？
Zombie-cons?
不能排除这种可能性
We cannot rule out the possibility
特别是 威震天似乎要去一个老地方
especially since Megatron seems to be heading to a familiar site.
啊 强大的天震葬身于此
Ah, the grave site of the mighty Skyquake.
生前你不假思索地拒绝我的领导
So quick to reject my authority while you lived
但作为被我复活的第一名战士
but as the first of my reanimated warriors
你应该听我号令！
you shall bow to my command!
是的…黑暗能量之力…是我的了！
Yesss... power of Dark Energon... be mine!
啊…融为一体 哈哈哈…我感觉到了！
Ahhh.... symbiosis... hahahahaha... I can feel it!
威震天刚从休眠中醒来不久
Megatron has barely emerged from stasis
看来他迫不及待要弥补损失的时间
and it seems he's already making up for lost time.
隔板 大黄蜂 救护车 准备出发
Bulkhead, Bumblebee, Ratchet, prepare to roll out.
我也去？
Me?
如果要对付的是黑暗能量
If we are dealing with Dark Energon
我可能需要你的专业知识
I may well require your expertise.
阿尔茜…
Arcee...
当环陆桥操作员 明白！
Bridge operator, got it!
干掉他 隔板 把心脏带回来
Go get'em, Bulkhead. Bring the heart.
无动于衷 这可不是神子的风格
That's not like Miko not wanna go.
她肯定在打什么鬼主意
She's definitely up to something.
快拦住她！
Make it a break!
那不安全！
It's not safe.
第一次参加僵尸虎大战 我决不能错过！
I'm not gonna miss my first zombie-cons' throwdown!
神子？
Miko?
那不是威震天！
That's not Megatron!
起来吧 天震！站起来！
Rise, Skyquake! Rise!
快来观赏活死人的战斗吧！
Let's see some fight of the living dead already!
神子 你在想什么？
Miko? What were you thinking?
她什么都没想
She wasn't.
嘿 上次我完全错过了
Hey, I totally missed out last time.
这次也许是惟一的机会 能抓拍几张照片
This could be my only chance to take some snaps.
我的手机 肯定是落在基地了
My cellphone. I must have dropped it back at base.
红蜘蛛！
Starscream.
汽车人？
Autobots?
投降吧！
Stand down.
要投降的是你！
You stand down.
你伤不了我\N黑暗能量已经流遍了我的经脉！
You cannot harm me while Dark Energon flows through my veins!
你打断了他的翅膀 他飞不起来了
You clipped his wing. He's grounded.
快啊 快啊 快站起来！
Come on, come on, rise already!
我是红蜘蛛指挥官
This is Commander Starscream
请向我的坐标紧急开启环陆桥
requesting emergency Ground Bridge to my coordinates.
真不敢相信 你害我丢了手机！
Ugrrr... I can't believe you make me lose my phone!
怎么成我的错了？
Eheh, how was this my fault?
噢 不
Oh, no.
基地呼叫擎天柱 孩子们不见了
Base to Optimus, the kids are missing.
我们已经看到了 立即打开环陆桥
We have a visual, send the GroundBridge immediately.
两个？你们三个！进我们的环陆桥 快！
Two? You three! Into our Ground Bridge, now!
走吧！
Come on！
救护车 怎么回事？
Ratchet, what is happening?
双重环陆桥的传送门之间 一定是产生了反馈
The dualing GroundBridge portals must be feeding back on each other.
神子…我们得把孩子们救出来
Miko... we gotta get the kids out of there.
我的手！
My arm!
不准提起这件事！谁都别说！
Not a word about this! To anyone!
你们没事吧？
Are you guys OK?
是的 我想没事
Yea, I think so.
刚…刚才是怎么了？
What.. what just happened?
我不敢肯定
I can't be certain
但如果同一坐标的两座环陆桥形成对流
but if two GroundBridges sent to the same coordinates crossed streams
反馈效应可能会引起系统超载
the feedback could have triggered the system overload.
可能？嘿 那简直是肯定的！
Could? Hello? More like totally did!
孩子们顺利通过了吧？
The kids made it through, right?
他这话什么意思？
What's he talking about?
隔板 我们在这儿呢！
Bulkhead, we are right here!
阿尔茜 孩子们安全回到基地了吗？
Arcee, did the children make it safely back to base?
没有 你们没看到他们吗？
Negative. You don't see them?
毫无踪影
No sign.
什么？毫无踪影？
What? No sign?
好吧 别闹了 小隔
OK, seriously Bulk?
哇！
Woaaah!
他从你身上穿了过去…
He went right through you.
我们不是活人！
We are not alive!
我不想变成鬼魂！
I don't wanna be a ghost!
等等 为什么我们之间能碰到？
Wait, how can we still touch each other?
救护车 孩子们有可能被
Ratchet, could the children have been
传送到报应号内部吗？
transported on to the Nemisis instead?
不大可能 既然红蜘蛛没有进入我们的基地
Not likely, if Starscream didn't arrive at our base.
最合理的解释就是定位混乱
The most likely explanation is a dislocation.
孩子们可能只是被传送到 一个随机的地点
The children may simply have been bridged to an unintended destination.
既不是这里 又正是这里？
Another place but in the same place?
你…你什么意思？
Wh... what do you mean?
我们很可能在另一个四维空间
We're probably in a different dimension.
另一种现实 一个暗影空间
Some kind of alternate reality, a shadowzone.
书呆子又来了
Nerd alert.
看 天震的墓空了
Look, Skyquake's tomb is empty.
天震死而复生 我们怎么会没发现？
How do we miss Skyquake rising and shining?
看来红蜘蛛得偿所愿了
It would seem Starscream got what he came for.
以后再考虑这个问题
Another matter for another time.
目前 我们的首要任务是找到杰克 神子和拉斐尔
Right now, our priority is locating Jack, Miko and Raphael.
阿尔茜 传送我们回基地
Arcee, bridge us back to base.
僵尸！
Zombie!
伙计们 小心！
Guys, look out!
隔板！
Bulkhead!
它就在你们后面！
It's right behind you!
太好了！连它也碰不到他们
Awesome! It can't touch them either.
如果那东西碰不到汽车人…
If that thing can't touch the Bots...
就跟我们一样
Just like we can't...
那么和我们一起被困在暗影空间的 就是个霸天虎僵尸！
Then we are trapped in a shadowzone, with a Decepticon zombie!
就算我们现在没死 变鬼魂也是迟早的事
If we aren't ghosts now, we will be soon.
快！
Come on!
杰克 我的眼镜！
Jack, my glasses!
太危险了
Way too dangerous.
没有眼镜 我什么都看不见
I can't see without them.
你怎么 七老八十了吗？
What are you, ninety？
别说风凉话！
Not helping!
好吧！
Fine!
等等！
Wait!
拿去吧 小老头 快跑
Here you go, gramps. Let's book.
也许能设一个陷阱 想办法砸坏它！
Maybe we could set up a trap, trying to crash it!
用什么砸？除了地上的尘土 这儿根本没有实物
With what? Nothing around here is solid except dusts on the ground.
我们不能一直逃下去 但或许能藏起来
We can't run forever. But maybe we can hide.
救护车 如果孩子们被误传到了未指定的地点
Ratchet, if the children were misdirected to an unintended location
有没有办法可以锁定他们的位置？
is there anyway to get a fix on their coordinates.
如果他们迷路了 神子应该会打电话给我的
If they were lost, Miko would have called me by now.
打给他们？没错！
Call them? Yes!
难怪神子没有打电话
That's why Miko hasn't phoned.
我试试打给杰克
Let me try Jack.
僵尸最好的一点就是 他们很慢 像爬一样
The best thing about zombies-- they are slow-moving.
- 是你的…\N- 电话！
Is that your...
喂 阿尔茜？
Hello, Arcee?
杰克 听见了吗？
Jack, can you hear me?
没声音
Nothing.
喂 阿尔茜？唉 没声音
Hello, Arcee? Uh, nothing.
天哪 谁想得到
Gee, imagine that
四维空间的手机信号这么差
the forth dimension has lausy cellphone reception.
嘿 伙计们…电话响了
Hey guys, guys, guys, the phone rang.
说明有信号
We are getting a signal.
汽车人看不见也听不见我们 可能是因为…
Maybe the Autobots can't see or hear us because...
我们也许在做超高速运动
we are moving at hyper speed or something.
你觉得他们能收到我们的信息吗？
Do you think that they could read us?
短信！
Texting!
给我发短信！如果我的手机在基地 他们或许能看到！
Text me! If my phone is back at base, maybe they'll see it!
呃…你能边跑边发吗？
Uh... can you type and run?
我们要在一大片扭曲力场中识别波动能量
We are dealling with fluctuating energy profiles inside a wide distortion field
不过 也许可以反向追踪到他们的坐标
but it may be possible to back-trace their coordinates.
似曾相识
Déjà vu
什么？
What?
你不觉得这里看起来很眼熟吗？
This doesn't look familiar to you?
不觉得
Not really.
老兄 我们只是在绕圈子！
Dude, we just ran one big circle!
太棒了！
Sweet!
它一定也是在爆炸时被困在这儿的
It must have gone trapped in here during the explosion, too.
既然这是个真家伙 我们就能用
Well, if it's solid, we can use it.
呃 红蜘蛛 我想不通 这是怎么搞的
Uh, Starscream, I don't quite understand how this could have happened.
不通也得通！
And yet, it did!
你能想象我有多惊慌吗？
Can you imagine my horror?
当时我在想事情 我的手臂突然自己掉了！
There I am, minding my own business, when my arm just falls off!
显然 威震天对我造成的伤害 不是你想的那么简单！
Clearly Megatron inflicted more damage upon me than you realize!
医生…
Doctor...
这样吧 想开点
Well, on the bright side
这正是个升级的绝好机会
this provides an excellent opportunity for an upgrade.
唔…我看看 你可以试试这个声波炮
Uh.. let's see, you could go with this sonic cannon.
很稳定 维护简单 只是不大气派
It's reliable, low maintenance, although it lacks of certain flare.
我个人推荐氖射线
Personally I prefer the null-ray.
闪光和火力的搭配恰到好处
It has just the right mix of flash and fire power.
我不想换新设备！
I don't want a new model!
我只想让我的手臂完好如初！
I just want the same arm I had before!
但是红蜘蛛 你的装备有点…过时了
But Starscream, your equipment is a bit... obsolete...
不知道还有没有废旧的备用品
I'm not sure I have another one lying around.
当然了 也可以尝试用原肢修复――原肢你还留着吧？
Of course we could try to salvage yours-- you kept it, didn't you?
已经…无法修复了
It was beyond recovery.
谁知道怎么发射这玩意儿？
Anyone know how to fire this thing?
我没看到扳机
I don't see a trigger.
红蜘蛛似乎是通过手指来操作的
Starscream did something with his fingers.
只能发射一次 要一击命中
We have one shot. We need to make it count.
还敢惹我们吗？
How do you like us now?
快 快！
Come on, come on!
为什么僵尸的手 比它本身跑得还快？
How can a zombie arm move faster than the actual zombie?
神子的电话
Miko's phone.
刚才它没闪过
It wan't blinking before.
是条信息
It's a message.
“与僵尸同被困在另一个空间 救命！”
"In alternate dimension with zombie. Help!"
听起来很离谱
That doesn't sound possible.
救护车 能确定手机信号的地理位置吗？
Ratchet, can we triangulate the geographical position
在平行四维空间里？
In a parallel dimensional plane?
我们试试看
Let's find out.
我的黑暗能量碎片
My Dark Energon shard.
有脉冲？我的战士还活着！
Pulsing? My warrior lives!
啊…看看我在仓库找到了什么
Ahh... Look what I found in storage.
你又干什么去？！
What are you doing?
你说的没错 击倒
You were right, Knock Out.
我跟原来的零件太有感情了
I'm much too attached to my original appendage.
我会找回来的
I will retrieve it.
通过计算相对时差和球面畸变数据
Now, calculating for relative time delays and iron spheric distortions
信号的发射源地点
the signal eminated from the exact location
和之前的环陆桥坐标完全相同！
as the original GroundBridge coordinates!
但我们在那儿找过了
But we already looked for them there.
虽然找过 但却找错了空间 如他们的短信所说
Perhaps, but not in the correct dimensional phase as their message stated.
不过 如果我重新启动引发事故的那个反馈循环
But, if I can recreate the feedback loop which triggered the event
应该能生成一个营救传送门
I might be able to generate a rescue portal
从他们所在的空间…
allowing passage from their dimension...
传送回基地？
Back to base?
不！这可是跨空间传送 隔板！
No! We are talking about inter-dimensional travel here, Bulkhead!
将漩涡轨道重新定向 风险太大！
Attempting to redirect the vortex trajectory would be far too risky.
大家都明白
Everyone knows that.
如果坐标不是绝对一致
If the coordinates aren't precisely the same
他们会被传送到哪儿 谁都不知道！
who knows where the humans could wind up?
噢 拜托！
Oh, come on!
这地方就像个大型旋转木马
This place is like one big merry-go-round.
天震？你的主人在召唤你！
Skyquake? You master summons you!
那个怪胎怎么跑进了我们的空间？
How'd that freak get into our dimension?
他没进来 他看不见我们
He didn't. He can't see us.
别管红蜘蛛了 我们得继续跑！
Forget Starscream, we get to run...
再跑一圈…
some more.
环陆桥传送门？
A GroundBridge portal?
一定是出口！
That has to be a way out of here.
汽车人看到我们的信息了
The Autobots saw our texts.
什么？我的？还是他们的？
What? Mine? Or theirs?
如果我们穿过去 一定会跟红蜘蛛碰面
If we go through, we will smack into Starscream.
如果我们不过去…
If we don't...
就变成僵尸的盘中餐
We are zombie chow.
还有第三个选择 继续绕圈跑
Option 3, we get running in circles.
听我口令
Follow my lead.
跑！
Now!
人类？你们这堆虫子从哪儿…
Humans? Where did you vermin...
不！
No!
这不是我的手…啊…
This isn't mine... ah... Unhand me!
杰克 神子 拉斐尔
Jack, Miko, Raphael.
啊 又是汽车人？
Ah, Autobots again?
请求开启紧急环陆桥 快！
Requesting emergency GroundBridge, now!
听着 如果要责备谁的话 就拿我开刀吧
Look, if you are gonna blame anybody, blame me.
不好意思 你能重说几十遍吗？
I'm sorry, could you repeat that a couple of dozen times?
神子 你的经历算是给你足够的教训了
Miko, what you endured has been lesson enough.
你们安然无恙 我们就放心了
We are just glad you are all safe.
幸好你落下了这个
Guess it was a good thing you dropped this.
可惜你一张照片都没拍到
Too bad you didn't get any pictures though.
算了 没什么
Nah, that's OK.
我想 从今以后
I think after today
僵尸的特写镜头 已经深深烙在我脑子里了
I pretty much have zombie close-up seared into my brain.
怎么回事？威震天又把你当破铜烂铁砸了一遍？
What happened? Megatron pound you like scrap metal again?
我不想提了
I would rather not discuss it.
老实说 红蜘蛛 你得善待自己一点
Honestly Starscream, you need to take better care of yourself.
你没捡回你的手臂吗？
Didn't you retrieve your limb?